{
    "id": "b72b071d6efe497296c93ab48eafd716",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is taller ……………….. her husband.",
            "description": "Then is  a time expression than is used in comparative structures. ",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He put the books ………………….. the table.",
            "description": "We use in to show position inside three dimensional spaces. On is used to show position on the surface of something. ",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Get the cat ……………….. the piano.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The baby ………………….. his mother.",
            "description": "Resemble is one of those verbs that do not take a preposition before its object. ",
            "answers": [
                "resembles",
                "resembles to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The child sat ………………….. his mother.",
            "description": "Beside means near or next to. Besides means in addition to.",
            "answers": [
                "beside",
                "besides"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The clown ....................... the audience with his tricks.",
            "description": "Amusing is a present participle form. It becomes a verb only when it is used with forms of be. ",
            "answers": [
                "amused",
                "amusing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is nursing a …………………. heart.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "broken",
                "breaking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is raining cats and ………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "mice",
                "dogs"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I gave ……………….. chemistry because I didn’t like it.",
            "description": "To give up is to stop making an effort and accept that you have failed. ",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t wait ……………….. the holidays.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "till",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don't know where ......................... gone.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has he",
                "he has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He is taller than ......................",
            "description": "If there is no verb, object pronouns are more common after than. ",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "I am",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}